Zekeriya Koç

http://zekzekus.github.com/

SUMMARY

I am working as an Oracle PL/SQL developer since 2004.

I have developed and maintained various systems in various sectors. Government, insurance, retail etc.

I develop software at high speed and quality with Oracle Forms/Reports and directly on database with PL/SQL.

Beside my Oracle profession i am an evangelist of open source. I use Linux for my personal development environment. My favourite languages are python, erlang, javascript, smalltalk, java, common lisp, php etc.

I love web programming and comfortable with client-server systems, HTTP protocol, client side (javascript) etc.

SKILLS

- Oracle
- SQL
- Java
- Glassfish
- Web Applications
- Ruby on Rails
- PHP
- Erlang
- Common Lisp
- Windows
- Nginx
- REST
- Git
- OOP
- Software Development
- Open Source
- JAXWS

- PL/SQL
- Python
- Web Services
- Django
- Ruby
- JavaScript
- Play Framework
- Haskell
- Linux
- Apache
- HTTP
- Web Development
- Subversion
- MySQL
- Databases
- JAXB
- NetBeans

EXPERIENCE

Ay Marka Mag. AS

Software Development Unit Manager

06 / 2010 - Present

A big textile retail company includes the famous brands Network, Fabrika, Beymen Bussiness, Altınyıldız Classics, Arzu Kaprol, Que, T-box, Divarese. I am responsible of the maintenance and development processes of the ERP part of in house developed system.

Main database is Oracle 10g RDBMS and Oracle Forms 6i/10g, Reports 6i/10g tools for user interface.

I made use of Oracle object system in my projects. I implemented some applications with object oriented facilities provided directly in database.

Beymen Boğaziçi Alboy A.Ş.

05 / 2007 - 06 / 2010

Software Projects Manager

Big textile retail company includes the brands T-box and Divarese. I was responsible all of the software projects. Maintenance of the in house developed ERP system mostly coded on Oracle database and Forms/Reports tools was my primary responsibility. My

team consist of one or two developer except me.

I manage the whole implementation/migration of a new ERP system called Nebim Winner. The planning, data migrating, testing and implementation was successfully done in six months.

Akademi Yazılım

09 / 2006 - 05 / 2007

Software Development Specialist

Company were offering all in one solutions to big insurance companies. Oracle RDBMS, Oracle Forms/Reports tools were our main development stack. I coded directly on database with PL/SQL language. I improved my SQL experience and skills on direct database programmable objects like stored procedures, functions, packages and triggers.

Sampaş Yazılım A.Ş.

06 / 2004 - 09 / 2006

Software Support Specialist

The company was developing software systems for all operations of municipalities. I was in a team supports customers directly. My responsibilities were; first analyze of the project, installation, data migration, training and continuous support including data mining operations, on the fly solutions includes code modifications etc.

I experienced with Oracle developer tools very first time here. I mainly code in Oracle Forms 6i and Oracle Reports 6i tools with PL/SQL, a Pascal like procedural programming language. Also, i gained high level of SQL experience here.

EDUCATION

Anadolu Üniversitesi

2007 - 2011

Bachelor of Science (BS), Bussiness Management

Celal Bayar Üniversitesi

2001 - 2003

Computer Programmer

INTERESTS

egzotic programming languages like python, haskell, lisp, erlang etc.

LANGUAGES

English (Professional working proficiency)

Turkish (Native or bilingual proficiency)

PUBLICATIONS

Smalltalk ile Yazılım Geliştirme

07 / 2007

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · http://ubuntuone.com/70WYOhLMrxRxpt9svb0qOP

A guide to basics of smalltalk development with Squeak. Turkish.

Deniz Kenarında Kısa Bir Gezinti: Seaside

02 / 2007

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · http://ubuntuone.com/0sw8K6yhHJDLugSLRrhOoK

Turkish translation of an article about Seaside Web Framework written in Smalltalk programming language

Emacs ile Oracle SQL*Plus ve "sql-mode"

01 / 2008

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · http://ubuntuone.com/3ubnc3wquY9XMYHmFmsyhA

A short article about to use emacs editor to connect oracle database and use as a interface to oracle's sql*plus utility

Ironpython: .NET üzerinde Python - Bölüm 1

11 / 2006

 $fazlamesai.net ~\cdot~ Authors: Zekeriya~ Koç ~\cdot~ \underline{http://ubuntuone.com/6WNYCqGYeP2oN7113WLGBz}$

Turkish translation of an article about Ironpython an implementation of Python language that sits on top of .NET framework. Part 1

Ironpython: .NET üzerinde Python - Bölüm 2

11 / 2006

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · http://ubuntuone.com/4nkt7nvT0YbG7Q8vJ0KIVY

Turkish translation of an article about Ironpython an implementation of Python language that sits on top of .NET framework. Part 2

Ironpython: .NET üzerinde Python - Bölüm 3

11 / 2006

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · http://ubuntuone.com/57WqaqCINhoopnp0nCSxiQ

Turkish translation of an article about Ironpython an implementation of Python language that sits on top of .NET framework. Part 3

UncommonWeb ile "Merhaba Dünya"

04 / 2007

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · http://ubuntuone.com/37Vk27HkqLoCJxjsn9X5My

A guide to the sophisticated web development framework written in Common Lisp language. Turkish.